A Guide to the Papers of Richard Watkins Carrington 1880-1933
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Richard Watkins Carrington 1880-1933
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2705
ca. 43,675 items (116 Hollinger boxes and six oversize folders, ca. 38 linear shelf feet)
This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of the corporation lawyer and civic leader, Richard Watkins Carrington (1889-1933) of Richmond, Virginia, and related Davenport Family.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Carrington papers were given to the University of Virginia Library on March 21, 1973, by Richard Watkins Carrington, Jr., of Richmond, Virginia.
Notes on the Carrington Family
Richard Watkins Carrington (1888-1933) was born in Richmond, Virginia, on May 19, 1888, to Tazewell Morton and Julia (Watkins) Carrington. Richard Carrington attended McGuire's University School of Richmond, and then entered Hampden-Sydney College, graduating in 1907 with a Bachelor of Arts degree. Carrington received his law degree from the University of Virginia in 1910, and belonged to the Richmond City, Virginia State, and American Bar Associations. Elected to the General Assembly as a Democrat, he served in the sessions of 1918 and 1919 on the general laws and insurance and banking committees. He was also a director of the Union Bank of Richmond, a member of the congregation of the Second Presbyterian Church, a member of the Board of Directors of the Country Club of Virginia, and a member of the Commonwealth Club. During the Great War, Carrington entered the Officer's Training School at Fort Monroe, but the armistice was signed before he saw active service. On November 4, 1915, Richard Carrington married Delia Davenport, a daughter of Charles and Ellen (McCaw) Davenport, residents of Richmond, Virginia. They had two children, Richard Watkins Carrington, Jr., born on January 9, 1917, and Delia Davenport, born on December 14, 1919. Charles Davenport was the son of Isaac Davenport, Jr. and Ellen (McCaw) Davenport, was the daughter of Dr. James B. McCaw.
Tazewell Morton Carrington (1857-?) was a prominent figure in the tobacco industry, serving as head of the Carrington Company in Richmond, Virginia, one of the largest businesses dealing in leaf tobacco, and president of the Tobacco Association of the United States. Tazewell Carrington was born in Richmond, Virginia, on February 21, 1857, to William Tucker and Bettie L. (Morton) Carrington. He was educated at the McGuire School at Richmond, and attended the University of Virginia for one year, 1875-1876. He has served as president of the Chamber of Commerce of Richmond, and as a director in both the First National Bank and the Mechanics and Merchants Bank of Richmond. During World War I, in 1918, T.M. Carrington was state chairman of the United War Work Campaign in Virginia. He was also a member and elder of the Second Presbyterian Church. He was married to Julia M. Watkins (d. 1900), daughter of Richard V. Watkins, on January 21, 1886, in Halifax County, and they had three sons: Richard W. Carrington, who married Delia Davenport; Tazewell M. Carrington, Jr., associated with his father in the Richmond tobacco business, who married Carter Ingram, and attended the University of Virginia, 1909-1911; and William Tucker Carrington, unmarried, who served overseas during the Great War with the Eightieth Division, A.E.F, and then became engaged in the manufacture of building supplies in Richmond.
The founder of the Carrington family in Virginia was George Carrington, who emigrated from the British Island of Barbados, West Indies, in 1712, marrying a Miss Mayo, and settling in Cumberland County, Virginia, as a farmer and planter. His son, Judge Paul Carrington, was born in Cumberland County, becoming a distinguished attorney, a member of the House of Burgesses, and in 1780, the chief justice of the General Court of Virginia. He married a Miss Read, and lived in Charlotte County, where his son, George Carrington, was born. George Carrington fought in the Revolutionary War and married a Miss Tucker; his son, the Honorable John Bonaparte Carrington, was born in Charlotte County, and fought in the War of 1812, before serving in the Virginia Legislature from 1823-1827 and 1835-1836 for Halifax County. John B. Carrington married Judith Winbish, a native of Halifax County. The grandfather of Richard Watkins Carrington was Captain William Tucker Carrington(1831- 1913), an officer of the Confederacy, and a tobacconist in Richmond. He married Bettie Lewis Morton(1836-1916) who was born in Farmville, Virginia. They had at least nine children:
Tazewell Morton Carrington m. Julia M. Watkins
John B. Carrington m. Leila Gamble
Tucker Lewis Carrington, unmarried
Judith Carrington m. Edward R. Stettinius
Bessie L. Carrington, unmarried
Randolph Carrington
Mary Carr, unmarried
Henry Paul Carrington, Jr. m. Hazel [Dimenick?]
Emma Carrington, unmarried
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of the corporation lawyer and civic leader, Richard Watkins Carrington (1889-1933) of Richmond, Virginia, and related Davenport Family. Carrington was a law student at the University of Virginia, 1907-1910. The papers, ca. 1880-1933, include legal case files, estate files, personal and family files, investment statements, bank registers and statements, bound volumes, blueprints, photographs, and financial records. The legal case files and the estate files include correspondence, insurance policies, property deeds, titles, wills, receipts, minutes of meetings, contracts, notes, and other related papers.
Organization
I) Legal Cases & Subject Files, arranged alphabetically by client name or subject (Boxes 1-84)
II) Estates, arranged alphabetically by client name (Boxes 85-94)
III) Personal and Family Papers
Subseries A: R.W. Carrington Personal (Boxes 95- 101)
Subseries B: Family Papers (Boxes 102-108)
IV) Bank Documents -Passbooks, Registers & Statements (Boxes 109- 113)
V) Bound Volumes & Artifacts in Mini-Tray 41 (Boxes 114-116, & 2M Ledgers)
VI) Oversize Folders (Oversize Tray 14 & Oversize Box M-21)
Contents List
- Legal Cases
  - Mayor Ainslie 1924 (Box 1)
  - Alabama Masonic Hospital, Inc. - Certificate of Incorporation, By-Laws, & Minutes ca. 1927-1929 (Box 1)
  - James T. Allensworth (bankruptcy) 1916-1918 (Box 1)
  - American Bar Association 1926-1930 (Box 1)
  - American Capital Envelope Company, Inc. 1930, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Hide and Leather Company 1925 (Box 1)
  - American Loan Company 1926-1927, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Paper Company 1931-1932, n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - American Tobacco Company 1921 (Box 2)
  - Colonel A.A. Anderson 1927-1933 (Box 2)
  - Anderson-Wilson Paper Company 1922-1926 (Box 2)
  - E.C. Anderton 1922-1923 (Box 2)
  - Anderton Auto 1922-1923 (Box 2)
  - Arenson vs. Blacker 1915 (Box 2)
  - Armistead Realty Company 1932 (Box 2)
  - Ivey L. Arrington 1923-1929 (Box 2)
  - Associated Charities of Richmond 1921-1923 (Box 2)
  - Atkins vs. Atkins 1927-1928 (Box 3)
  - Hunter Atkinson 1928-1933 (Box 3)
  - Atlantic Coast Line Railroad Company 1928-1930 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous "A" 1917-1929 (Box 3)
  - C.H. Baab n.d. (Box 3)
  - Barker vs. Barker 1916-1926 (Box 3)
  - Barker Bakeries 1919-1933, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Barker Bakeries - Financial & Legal Papers 1919-1932, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Barnard and Moore 1929-1934, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Bartlett Navigation Company 1918-1920 (Box 4)
  - Bellvue Garage 1916-1917 (Box 5)
  - Beneficial Loan Society 1919-1924, n.d., 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Blue Sky Application 1920-1922, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - City License Tax 1920-1921 (Box 6)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Commonwealth vs. 1920 (Box 6)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - C.F. Delmar and Company 1922-1923 (Box 6)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Lynchburg 1920-1929 (Box 6)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Norfolk 1921-1922 (Box 7)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - North Carolina Legislation 1922-1923 (Box 7)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Roanoke 1922-1923 (Box 7)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Stocks 1923 (Box 7)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Virginia Legislation 1921-1922 (Box 7)
  - Beneficial Loan Society - Miscellaneous 1919-1922 (Box 8)
  - Berlin and Jones Stationery Company 1927-1932 (Box 8)
  - Berlin and Jones Stationery Company - Financial & Legal Papers 1927-1932, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Berman vs. Stueber 1915-1916, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Boe [Bowe?] vs. Livingstone 1915 (Box 8)
  - Bowe vs. Russell 1921 (Box 8)
  - Boyle vs. Deane 1909-1915 (Box 8)
  - Boyle vs. Moyer 1916 (Box 8)
  - Brinkley vs. Kline Kar Sales Corporation 1919 (Box 8)
  - Brooks vs. Brooks (divorce) 1911-1913 (Box 9)
  - Dr. Samuel Budd 1915-1924 (Box 9)
  - Buffalo Mineral Springs Water Company 1918-1921 (Box 9)
  - Charles H. Bull 1925 (Box 9)
  - Burrall vs. Burrall (divorce) 1923-1924 (Box 9)
  - Burt vs. Hofheimer 1913-1914 (Box 9)
  - Lucy Butler 1912-1919 (Box 9)
  - Buxton Line, Inc. 1921 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous "B" 1913-1929, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Harry Cantor 1928 (Box 10)
  - Forest Carpenter 1929-1933 (Box 10)
  - Central Storage Corporation 1923 (Box 10)
  - Lord Robert Cecil 1923 (Box 11)
  - Chamberlain Metal Weather Strip Company 1927-1929 (Box 11)
  - Chesapeake Amusement Company 1923-1926, n.d., 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Chinese Immigration Cases 1929-1931 (Box 11)
  - Christo Cola Bottling Company 1916 (Box 11)
  - Citizens Loan Company 1920-1923 (Box 12)
  - Citizens and Marine Bank of Newport News 1924 (Box 12)
  - Coal Mining and Lumber Company 1928-1932 (Box 12)
  - H.T. Cole 1925-1927 (Box 12)
  - College Men's Corporation 1924-1931 (Box 12)
  - Collegiate School for Girls 1920-1932, n.d., 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Commercial Investment Trust, Inc. 1922-1923 (Box 13)
  - J.C. Cone 1919-1920 (Box 13)
  - Dennis Conners 1921-1927 (Box 13)
  - Continental Insurance Company 1922 (Box 13)
  - Country Club of Virginia 1924-1930, n.d. (Box 14)
  - A.E. Covington 1931 (Box 14)
  - S.H. Cox 1916-1917 (Box 14)
  - Credit Finance Company of Richmond, Inc. 1921-1922 (Box 14)
  - Credit Union National Extension Bureau 1922-1933, n.d., 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Robert Crews 1927-1928 (Box 15)
  - J.L. Crouse 1926-1932 (Box 15)
  - Benjamin T. Crump Company, Inc. 1919-1926, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Benjamin T. Crump Company, Inc. - Financial & Legal Papers 1920-1929, n.d., 3 folders (Box 16)
  - E.M. Crutchfield 1914-1918, n.d., 2 folders (Box 16)
  - J.W. Cunningham 1925-1926 (Box 16)
  - John Curzon 1927 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous "C" 1910-1931, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Dabney Brothers, Inc. 1918 (Box 17)
  - Dad's Incorporated 1924 (Box 17)
  - Davenport Insurance Company 1920-1932 (Box 17)
  - Davenport Insurance Company - E. Conway Brown 1917-1918 (Box 18)
  - Davenport Insurance Company vs. Virginia Trust Company 1919-1923 (Box 18)
  - J.A. Davis 1931 (Box 18)
  - C.F. Delmar and Company 1923-1926 (Box 18)
  - Benjamin Dobson 1914-1916 (Box 18)
  - Henry Doherty and Company 1929-1930 (Box 18)
  - Dolfy vs. Dolfy 1917-1921 (Box 18)
  - Edloe Dunnon 1921-1922 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous "D" 1919-1929 (Box 19)
  - Eastern Brick Company 1923-1930 (Box 19)
  - Eastern Brick Company - Financial and Legal Papers 1921-1931, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Eastern Brick Company - Bankruptcy 1930-1931 (Box 19)
  - Eastern Brick Company vs. Gas Boat "Davidson" 1923-1925 (Box 20)
  - Eastern Brick Company vs. Jennings and Spencer 1924-1925 (Box 20)
  - J.S. Edge 1923 (Box 20)
  - Jerone Edmunson - Kentucky-Virginia Mining Corporation 1927-1929 (Box 20)
  - Jerone Edmunson - Hospital Realty Corporation of Woodlawn 1927-1933 (Box 20)
  - Jerone Edmunson - Alabama Hospital Incorporated 1927-1930 (Box 20)
  - Eisenminger vs. Swan 1913 (Box 20)
  - Elderslie Land Corporation 1924-1925 (Box 20)
  - William Ellett 1919-1920 (Box 20)
  - J.B. Eskew 1913-1914 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous "E" 1919-1928 (Box 21)
  - W.M. Faber 1924-1925 (Box 21)
  - Fennell vs. Highland Park 1912-1916 (Box 21)
  - First and Merchants National Bank 1927-1930 (Box 21)
  - First National Bank of Danville 1927 (Box 21)
  - John C. Freeman 1922-1925 (Box 21)
  - William Frye 1925-1930 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous "F" 1921-1930 (Box 22)
  - Gale Brothers Incorporated 1925-1926 (Box 22)
  - H.P. Garber 1919 (Box 22)
  - John Garrett 1916-1919 (Box 22)
  - Georgia Land and Live Stock Company 1921-1923 (Box 22)
  - J.A. and L.W. Gills 1919 (Box 22)
  - Glebe Estates, Inc. 1926-1929 (Box 22)
  - Glebe Estates, Inc. - Certificate of Incorporation, By-Laws, & Minutes ca. 1926 (Box 22)
  - Gordon Motor Company 1912-1916 (Box 22)
  - R.H. Gray 1924-1929 (Box 23)
  - Greensboro Music Company 1931-1932 (Box 23)
  - Henry Grimmell 1922 (Box 23)
  - Conrad Gross 1916-1919 (Box 23)
  - Richard Gwathmey 1924 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous "G" 1916-1932 (Box 23)
  - Hampden-Sydney Alumni Association 1920-1930 (Box 23)
  - Hampton Institute 1922-1923 (Box 23)
  - J.B. Hancock 1923-1924 (Box 23)
  - Mary S. Hancock 1923-1925 (Box 24)
  - Charles M. Harris 1916-1918 (Box 24)
  - F.J. Hassleman 1915-1917 (Box 24)
  - Sarah Haviland 1924-1925, n.d., 4 folders (Box 24)
  - S.H. Hawes and Company n.d. (Box 25)
  - Thomas Herbert 1922-1932 (Box 25)
  - Hillyar vs. Hillyar (divorce) 1931-1932 (Box 25)
  - Robert Hoffman (bankruptcy) 1916-1917 (Box 25)
  - Home Owner's Corporation 1919-1924 (Box 25)
  - Arthur Horner 1920-1921 (Box 25)
  - Hospital Realty Corporation of Woodlawn - Certificate of Incorporation, By-Laws, & Minutes ca. 1927-1930 (Box 25)
  - William C. Hudson 1921-1922 (Box 25)
  - Harold Hunt 1915-1917 (Box 25)
  - Pearl Hunter 1920 (Box 25)
  - Hunter and Company 1922-1925 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous "H" 1912-1930, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Inter-Club Council of Richmond 1926-1927 (Box 26)
  - International Relations Committee 1926-1927 (Box 26)
  - Inter-Racial Committee 1920-1928 (Box 26)
  - Inter-Racial Committee 1929-1933, n.d., 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Invitations/Appointments 1921-1930 (Box 27)
  - J.T. Irving 1913-1916 (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous "I" 1918-1930 (Box 27)
  - Jacob Jacobson 1930-1931 (Box 27)
  - Thomas Jacobson 1927-1928 (Box 27)
  - Jeffreys, Hester and Company 1912-1915 (Box 27)
  - Joseph Johnson 1923-1931 (Box 27)
  - Julien Johnson 1915-1918 (Box 28)
  - Leo Johnson 1925 (Box 28)
  - George Jones 1921-1922 (Box 28)
  - George & Thomas Jordan 1913-1920, n.d., 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Joshua Creek Mining Company 1916-1921 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous "J" 1918-1927 (Box 28)
  - Sol H. Kahn 1917 (Box 29)
  - J.P. Keen 1925-1926 (Box 29)
  - Robert Kent 1920-1921 (Box 29)
  - Keystone Service Corporation 1922-1932, n.d., 3 folders (Box 29)
  - King Motor Company 1920-1921 (Box 29)
  - Margaret Kirkpatrick 1928-1936, n.d., 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Kiwanis Club 1919-1929, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Gus Kohn Company 1918-1925, n.d., 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous "K" 1916-1932 (Box 30)
  - George Lamb 1920-1922 (Box 31)
  - T.A. Lamb 1910-1922 (Box 31)
  - William Lamb 1917 (Box 31)
  - George Lambert 1929 (Box 31)
  - C.P. Lanthrop & Company 1919-1921 (Box 31)
  - Larus & Brothers Company 1920-1926 (Box 31)
  - Laurel Glen Estates 1926-1927 (Box 31)
  - C.V. Layman 1924-1927 (Box 31)
  - H. Levine 1924-1927 (Box 31)
  - W.C. Locker 1929-1930 (Box 31)
  - Charles Loeber 1923-1927 (Box 32)
  - Loew's Incorporated 1930 (Box 32)
  - A.H. Lusk 1930-1932 (Box 32)
  - B.J. Lyon 1909-1917 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous "L" 1916-1932 (Box 32)
  - Fanny Marchant 1923-1929 (Box 32)
  - Morton Marks 1924-1927 (Box 32)
  - Sadie Martin 1925-1927 (Box 32)
  - Marshall Realty Corporation 1920-1927 (Box 32)
  - Marshall Realty Corporation 1928-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Belle Mason 1915-1916 (Box 33)
  - Maury Land Corporation 1923-1924 Aug (Box 33)
  - Maury Land Corporation 1924 Sep-1927, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Mayo Island Park, Inc. 1923-1929, n.d., 4 folders (Box 34)
  - James McCaw/William Moncure 1915-1917 (Box 35)
  - J.R. McConnell 1913-1914 (Box 35)
  - W.E. McCullough 1930 (Box 35)
  - Joseph McGarl 1919 (Box 35)
  - A.P. McKee 1918 (Box 35)
  - Frank McKinney 1928-1929 (Box 35)
  - Mechanics & Merchants Bank 1911-1930, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Mechanics & Merchants Bank n.d., 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Laura Melton 1912-1916 (Box 36)
  - Merchants Bank of Augusta 1915-1919, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Merchants Bank of Augusta n.d. (Box 37)
  - Michanx Tobacco Blending Machine Corporation 1930-1932 (Box 37)
  - Clifton Miller 1914 (Box 37)
  - Cary Montagne 1927-1928 (Box 37)
  - Motion Picture Theatre Owners 1922-1924, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Motion Picture Theatre Owners 1925-1932, n.d., 2 folders (Box 38)
  - David Murr 1916 (Box 38)
  - Charles James Murray 1927-1928 (Box 38)
  - Mutual Building & Loan Association, Inc. 1923 (Box 38)
  - A.E. Myers & Company 1920-1921 (Box 38)
  - Mary Myma 1917 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous "M" 1914-1931, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Naser, Katen & Nahass 1914-1915 (Box 39)
  - National Credit Association 1931-1932 (Box 39)
  - National Equitable Investment Company 1922-1927 Mar, 4 folders (Box 40)
  - national Equitable Investment Company 1927 May-1929, n.d., 3 folders (Box 41)
  - National Equitable Investment Company - Proxies 1926 May 3-4 (Box 41)
  - National Equitable Investment Company - Proxies 1926 May 5-July, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - National State and City Bank 1913-1922 (Box 42)
  - New Amsterdam Casualty Company 1917-1919, 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Newbern Company 1917-1918 (Box 43)
  - Nolting First Mortgage Corporation 1932 Apr-Oct (Box 43)
  - Nolting First Mortgage Corporation 1932 Nov-1933, n.d. (Box 44)
  - Herman Noreck 1914-1915 (Box 44)
  - Mary R. Norment 1918-1923 (Box 44)
  - Ravee Norris and Company, Inc. 1923 (Box 44)
  - NYVA Realty Corporation 1924-1933, 3 folders (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous "N" 1924-1932 (Box 45)
  - Old Dutch Market 1915-1923 Jul, 4 folders (Box 45)
  - Old Dutch Market 1923 Aug-1929, n.d., 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Old Dutch Market n.d. (Box 47)
  - Joseph Osborne 1922-1923 (Box 47)
  - Robert Osthimer 1926-1929 (Box 47)
  - Overland Motor Company, Inc. 1915-1918 (Box 47)
  - A.K. Parker 1922 (Box 48)
  - Annie parker 1917 (Box 48)
  - Charlie Parker 1920-1921 (Box 48)
  - C.R. Parmele 1915-1918 (Box 48)
  - Parr vs. Parr (divorce) 1918 (Box 48)
  - Helen Parrot 1926 (Box 48)
  - J.H. Patterson 1913-1917 (Box 48)
  - Patton, Temple & Williamson 1917-1918 (Box 48)
  - Harry Paulos 1915-1917 (Box 48)
  - Victorine Pavy 1916-1919 (Box 48)
  - W.J. Payne 1923 (Box 48)
  - O.G. Pearson 1915-1916 (Box 49)
  - Pencil Products Corporation 1922-1923 (Box 49)
  - Pennsyvania Casualty Company 1908-1915 (Box 49)
  - Peroe vs. Peroe (divorce) 1919-1920 (Box 49)
  - George Perry 1916-1917 (Box 49)
  - J.C. Phaup 1915-1929, n.d., 2 folders (Box 49)
  - J.C. Phaup n.d. (Box 50)
  - Planters National Bank 1909,1913-1920 Jul, 4 folders (Box 50)
  - Planters National Bank 1920 Aug-1924, n.d., 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Plaza Theatre 1925 (Box 51)
  - W.A. Plecker 1915-1922 (Box 51)
  - John Plunkett 1917-1920 (Box 51)
  - John Pollard 1929 (Box 52)
  - William J. Powell 1914-1916 (Box 52)
  - Powhatan Heights 1912-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 52)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc. 1920-1924 (Box 53)
  - Presbyterian League 1924-1926 (Box 53)
  - C.F. Prettyman 1916-1917 (Box 53)
  - Purse Printing Company 1922 (Box 53)
  - A.J. Pyle 1917 (Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous "P" 1915-1933 (Box 53)
  - M. Barbour Rahm 1923-1924 (Box 54)
  - Ready Brick Company 1921-1924, n.d., 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Reconstruction Finance Corporation 1932 (Box 54)
  - Peter Redd 1914-1915 (Box 54)
  - William Reed 1917-1918 (Box 54)
  - Samuel Regester 1912-1924 (Box 54)
  - D.J. Reinhardt 1929 (Box 54)
  - Anne Renshaw 1916 (Box 54)
  - Republic Land & Development Corporation 1927-1930 (Box 54)
  - Republic Paper & Products Company 1928-1929 (Box 54)
  - Retail Merchants Association 1918-1920 (Box 54)
  - H.C. Reynolds 1925-1926 (Box 54)
  - Howell Richardson 1917 (Box 54)
  - Richmond Auto Clearing House 1915 (Box 54)
  - Richmond Bar Association 1928-1931 (Box 54)
  - Richmond Baseball Club 1922-1928 (Box 55)
  - Richmond Battlefield Parks Corporation 1927-1931 (Box 55)
  - Richmond Buggy Manufacturing Company, Inc. 1913-1922 (Box 55)
  - Richmond Chamber of Commerce 1915-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 55)
  - Richmond Community Fund 1926-1927 (Box 56)
  - Richmond National Theatre Company 1911-1932, 2 folders (Box 56)
  - Richmond-New York Steamship Company [Eastern Steamship Lines, Inc.] 1898-1921 Jun (Box 56)
  - Richmond-New York Steamship Company [Eastern Steamship Lines, Inc.] 1921 Jul-1925 Jul, 4 folders (Box 57)
  - Richmond-New York Steamship Company [Eastern Steamship Lines, Inc.] 1925 Aug-1927, 5 folders (Box 58)
  - Richmond-New York Steamship Company [Eastern Steamship Lines, Inc.] 1928-1933, n.d., 3 folders (Box 59)
  - Richmond Postal Credit Union 1923-1929 (Box 59)
  - Richmond Tobacco Storage Company, Inc. 1907 (Box 59)
  - Richmond Urban League 1923-1926 (Box 59)
  - Rider vs. Rider (divorce) 1922-1924 (Box 59)
  - Frederick C. Righter 1918 (Box 59)
  - L.H. Riney 1923-1924 (Box 59)
  - George Roberts 1929 (Box 59)
  - Louise Robinson 1927 (Box 59)
  - Nina Furr Robinson 1923-1924 (Box 60)
  - Polly Robinson 1913-1925 (Box 60)
  - Joel Russell 1917-1918 (Box 60)
  - Paris Russell 1919 (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous "R" 1911-1930 (Box 60)
  - Sabbath Glee Club 1924-1926 (Box 60)
  - St. Paul's Church 1921-1930 (Box 60)
  - D. Salbst and Sons 1921-1922 (Box 60)
  - Salvation Army, Inc. 1921-1923 (Box 60)
  - C.A. Sandys 1914-1915 (Box 60)
  - Charles Saunders 1916-1918 (Box 60)
  - Schmidt vs. Schmidt 1917 (Box 60)
  - Morris Schorr 1926-1927 (Box 60)
  - Percy Seaton 1915-1929 (Box 61)
  - Dallas Shafer 1912-1916 (Box 61)
  - E.W. Shewmake 1923-1924 (Box 61)
  - J.J. Shore 1916-1918 (Box 61)
  - Simmons Company 1913-1932, n.d., 3 folders (Box 61)
  - John Sledd 1915-1916 (Box 62)
  - Sloan vs. Long 1929 (Box 62)
  - James C. Smith and Company 1928-1929 (Box 62)
  - Richard Smith 1913 (Box 62)
  - W.R. Smith (bankrupt) 1919-1920 (Box 62)
  - F.L. Smithe Machine Company 1929 (Box 62)
  - Southern Briquette Coal Company [Richmond Briquetting Corporation] 1911-1918, n.d., 2 folders (Box 62)
  - Southern Cotton Oil Company 1918-1921 (Box 62)
  - Southern Manufacturing Company 1923-1929 (Box 63)
  - Southern Manufacturing Company - Charter, By-Laws, & Minutes 1922-1923 (Box 63)
  - Southern Trunk & Bag Company, Inc. 1920-1925 (Box 63)
  - Spicer vs. Spicer 1919 (Box 63)
  - J.G. Spofford 1916-1918 (Box 63)
  - J.L. Stallings 1931-1932 (Box 63)
  - William Carrinton Stettinius (son of Edward Stettinius) 1916-1927 (Box 63)
  - Luella Stewart 1922-1923 (Box 63)
  - Stonega Coke & Coal Company 1929 (Box 63)
  - Julius Straus and Sons 1925-1932 (Box 63)
  - Gordon E. Strause 1924 (Box 63)
  - Strawberry Hill Land Corporation 1917-1931 (Box 64)
  - Mary Dallas Street 1926-1932, n.d., 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Student's Shop Inc. 1931 (Box 64)
  - Suffolk News Company 1931 (Box 64)
  - Sunnyside Quarry Corporation 1920-1925, n.d., 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Sunnyside Quarry Corporation - daybook & Ledger with index 1921 (Box 64)
  - Sutton and Company 1930-1931 (Box 64)
  - Swartz Enterprises, Inc. 1924-1927 (Box 65)
  - Lillian Sydnor 1917 (Box 65)
  - M.R. Snyder 1919 (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous "S" 1912-1930, 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Gervas Taylor 1922-1924 (Box 65)
  - Teller-Protector Company 1922-1931 (Box 65)
  - The Theatres, Inc. 1919-1931, n.d., 3 folders (Box 66)
  - L.P. Thomas 1923-1928 (Box 66)
  - Edward Thompson Company 1912-1919 (Box 66)
  - Lulu Threatt 1925-1927 (Box 66)
  - J. McCaw Tompkins 1919-1931 (Box 66)
  - William Tottle & Co., Inc. 1925 (Box 67)